<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on AndyTheCoder</title>
    <link>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on AndyTheCoder</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sticker on Laptop breaks warranty (according to eBuyer)</title>
      <link>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/hardware/sticker-on-laptop-breaks-warranty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/hardware/sticker-on-laptop-breaks-warranty/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR  A sticker on your laptop is &amp;lsquo;damage&amp;rsquo; and breaks your warranty Well, according to eBuyer&amp;hellip; Reading their linkedIn page: &amp;lsquo;We pride ourselves on our customer service&amp;rsquo;  I would beg to differ   eBuyer has refused to honour the Consumer Rights Act 2015 claiming that a sticker on a laptop voids their obligations under the act. They claim that a sticker invalidates the warranty, yet refuse to produce the warranty, let alone show where in the warranty it states that a sticker on a laptop is &amp;lsquo;damage&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# is not</title>
      <link>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/c-sharp/not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/c-sharp/not/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR if (myVar is not null) DoSomething(); New C# 9 keyword: not One of the smaller (less headline grabbing) additions to C# 9 is pattern matching (enhancements). And one of the smaller, but probably one of the features that will be most used, is the &amp;lsquo;not&amp;rsquo; keyword.
Previously a common &amp;lsquo;not null&amp;rsquo; check would be: // no longer recommended as equals operator can be over-ridden if (myVar != null) DoSomething(); // hard to read if (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blazor Charts using Blazorise</title>
      <link>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/c-sharp/blazorise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/c-sharp/blazorise/</guid>
      <description>Demo of Blazorise which is a component library for Blazor. One of the interesting components is charting, which is a blazor wrapper for Chart.js
This live demo shows client side blazor (wasm) generating charts
Links  live demo: wasm blazor charts blazorise: https://blazorise.com/ chart docs: https://blazorise.com/docs/extensions/chart/ repo: https://github.com/andyTheCoder/blazorise-demo  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asp.Net MVC Adding Blazor Server</title>
      <link>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/c-sharp/asp-net-mvc-add-blazor-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/c-sharp/asp-net-mvc-add-blazor-server/</guid>
      <description>Overview Walk through taking an existing asp.net mvc app and adding server side blazor support.
Pre-requisits  an existing asp.net mvc app running .net 5  New files _Imports.razor default using statements for blazor components  App.razor blazor routing  Pages/Counter.razor blazor component  Changed files startup.cs add blazor server side (no default blazor routing as routing handled by mvc)  Index.cshtml add blazor component to existing mvc view  Notes  this post demonstrates adding a blazor component to an existing mvc view page original mvc code base is mvc visual studio template additional code comes from blazor server side visual studio template this is not client side blazor aka wasm watch out for casing; blazor components must start capitalized   Code links  repo: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# 9 records</title>
      <link>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/c-sharp/records/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/c-sharp/records/</guid>
      <description>Records: immutable classes show me the code&amp;hellip;
  github repo: https://github.com/andyTheCoder/c-sharp-9
References
 https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/c-9-0-on-the-record/ https://channel9.msdn.com/Shows/On-NET/C-9-Language-Features?ocid=player https://daveabrock.com/2020/11/02/csharp-9-records-immutable-default  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PC USB always on</title>
      <link>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/hardware/pc-usb-always-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/hardware/pc-usb-always-on/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR  to switch usb power off when shutting pc down: enable ErP setting in bios to S4+S5.  All my usb devices were still on when my pc was shut down  I bought a new microphone which had an led on it. When the pc was shut down, the light was still on, annoying more than anything else.
I tried the windows 10 power options to no avail. After googling I found some people mentioning a bios setting S5&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curl a message to Microsoft Teams</title>
      <link>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/teams/curl-message-to-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/teams/curl-message-to-teams/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR  create a connector of type: &amp;lsquo;incoming webhook&amp;rsquo; to the teams channel you want to post to and copy the generated url create a curl command view your teams message   Create the connector (aka webhook)   select the channel you want to create a connector for:   add an &amp;lsquo;incoming webhook&amp;rsquo;:   click add:   name the connector (Note this name will appear in teams as the message sender)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# and underscores</title>
      <link>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/c-sharp/underscores/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/c-sharp/underscores/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR  an underscore in c# is a variable that you do not care about; they are called discards an underscore is a digit separator   Underscores as discards unsplash-logoShane Rounce
So if you see code like this:
var (_, _, _, pop1, _, pop2) = QueryCityDataForYears(&amp;#34;New York City&amp;#34;, 1960, 2010);The 1st, 2nd, 3rd &amp;amp; 5th values of the returned tuple; we don&#39;t care about. Discards were introduced in c# 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My DNS disappeared</title>
      <link>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/dns/my-dns-disappeared/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/dns/my-dns-disappeared/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR  when moving nameservers to cloudflare; make sure the domain contact emails are valid.  My DNS disappeared  When setting up this blog I used (re-used) andythecoder.com. I wanted to route through cloudflare, mainly (but not only) for the free ssl.
NB. I  cloudflare.
I have gone through the process of moving nameservers from a domain registrar to cloudflare many times, always without a hitch&amp;hellip; but this time the domain simply vanished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>404 ascii art hugo page</title>
      <link>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/hugo/404-ascii-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/hugo/404-ascii-art/</guid>
      <description>Demo: https://blog.andythecoder.com/404.html  Created the ascii art using: http://patorjk.com/software/taag/#p=display&amp;amp;f=Doh&amp;amp;t=4%200%204 Wrap the ascii art in pre tag Hugo 404 page setup: https://gohugo.io/templates/404/  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 11:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.andythecoder.com/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Welcome My intetion is to blog about tech that comes my way. This blog is running hugo and hosted as a github page (all free)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>